whyenglishmatters.com 2016-06-23

# ETS Legal: Privacy and Security

Educational Testing Service ("ETS") recognizes the importance of protecting your privacy. In addition to the commitments set out in this Privacy Policy, ETS has taken steps to meet legal obligations in various countries with the aim of compliance with worldwide data privacy requirements. ETS will strive to treat your "personal data" according to applicable local laws which regulate inter-country process, access and transfer of personal data. This Privacy Policy ("Policy") discloses our information-gathering and dissemination practices for this website at www.ets.org ("Website"). 

By using this Website, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Policy and the Terms of Use. You may also be subject to another privacy policy or other terms and conditions that are posted on ETS's Website specific to a particular ETS program or service ("Other Agreement"). Based upon your specific relationship(s) with ETS, we may collect, use or disclose Personal Information (defined below) in ways described in more detail in one or more Other Agreements. To the extent the Other Agreement includes additional terms that are not covered by or are inconsistent with this Policy, the terms and conditions of the Other Agreement will supersede this Policy.

Within this Policy you will find:

  * Children
  * Information We Collect
    * Personal Information
    * Nonpersonal Information
    * Cookies
    * Third-party Advertisers
  * How We Use Your Personal Information
  * Disclosure of Your Personal Information
  * Choice to Opt Out and Access to Your Information
  * Links to Third-party Sites
  * Security
  * Changes
  * Governing Law and Jurisdiction
  * Contact Information
  * Protect Yourself: Watch Out for Online Fraud
  * Special Notice to California Residents

## Children

We do not knowingly collect Personal Information (as defined below) online from children under the age of 13. If a child provides us with this type of information online, please contact us to have the account deactivated by sending us an email at [etsinfo@ets.org](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org) or by calling us at **1-609-921-9000**.

Back to Top

## Information We Collect

### Personal Information

We collect and store Personal Information that you provide voluntarily when using our Website. Personal Information is information that can identify you as a specific individual ("Personal Information"). You are responsible for providing accurate and complete information. For example, you might provide us the following information: responses and survey information and/or site registrations, test registration information, order information and payment information. Personal data does not include anonymized aggregate or statistical information from which such identification cannot be reconstituted.

If you register for a test, create an online account, or request one of our other services, we may collect the following Personal Information: full name, home address, email address, telephone number, Social Security number, passport number, and your answers to other similar background information questions, the test you are registering for, test date, payment information and how you specifically use our Website. Depending on how you use the Website, your test results may also be accessed through the Website. 

Back to Top

### Nonpersonal Information

When you visit any page on our Website, we use a program that monitors and evaluates the Website's traffic. It automatically records every visitor's host, domain name, pages visited, length of user session, browser type and/or IP address. This information does not contain Personal Information. We use this information to find out how many people visit the Website to determine the areas of greatest interest on our Website, and to make improvements to the Website. 

When you visit and interact with our Website, ETS and third parties with whom ETS has contracted to provide services to ETS may collect nonpersonal information (for example, a catalog of the site pages you visit, or your IP address).

Back to Top

### Cookies

Generally, as an enterprise, our systems do not support "Do Not Track" capabilities.

As with many other sites, our Website may use "cookies" or other technologies to help us deliver content specific to your interests, to process your reservations or requests, and/or to analyze your visiting patterns. We may collect the following types of information about your visit including: the domain from which you access the Internet; IP address; operating system and information about the device or browser used when visiting the site; date and time of your visit; content you visited or downloaded; and website (such as google.com or bing.com) and website referral source (email notice or social media site) that connected you to the website. ETS uses third-party measurement software to collect the information listed above.

There are two types of cookies: single-session (temporary) and multi-session (persistent). Temporary cookies last only as long as your Web browser is open, and are used for technical purposes such as enabling better navigation through our site. Once you close your browser, the cookie disappears. Persistent cookies are stored on your computer for longer periods and are used for purposes including tracking the number of unique visitors to our site and information such as the number of views a page gets, how much time a user spends on a page, and other pertinent web statistics.

Cookies, by themselves, will not be used by ETS to disclose your individual identity. This information identifies your browser, but not you, to our servers when you visit the Website. If you want to disable the use of cookies or remove them at any time from your computer, you can disable or delete them using your browser (consult your browser's "Help" menu to learn how to delete cookies); however, you must enable cookies to access certain information on our Website. Note that in limited instances, such as when you register for a test or create an online account, cookies may contain and be associated with the Personal Information we collect.

We may also collect data by using "pixel tags," "web beacons," "clear GIFs" or similar means (collectively, "pixel tags") that allow us to know when you visit our Website. Through pixel tags, we obtain nonpersonal information or aggregate information (i.e., your IP address, the areas of the Website you visit, your operating system, your browser version and the URL you came from) which can be used to enhance your online experience and understand traffic patterns.

Back to Top

### Third-party Advertisers

In addition, we may use third-party advertisers to serve or track advertisements on other websites. Please note that these third parties also may use cookies, pixel tags and other technologies to, among other things, enable such third parties to record which ads your browser has loaded and which site pages you may have been viewing when the ads were delivered or accessed. Use of such third-party sites is subject to the terms of use and privacy policies of those third parties. ETS does not control the use of this technology or the resulting information and is not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties. 

Back to Top

## How We Use Your Personal Information

We use your Personal Information to:

  * complete any registration, purchases or other transactions you request online
  * improve the Website
  * improve our products and services, and identify, develop and offer new or expanded products and services
  * personalize your experience on the Website, and customize the content and/or format of the pages you visit
  * notify you about updates, products, services and/or special offers from ETS, its affiliates and selected third parties
  * ask you to participate in brief surveys
  * generate aggregate statistical studies and conduct research related to our products and services and the use of our Website

Based upon your specific relationship(s) with ETS, we may use your Personal Information in ways described in more detail in one or more Other Agreements. 

Back to Top

## Disclosure of Your Personal Information

We disclose your Personal Information to certain third parties with whom we have a direct or indirect business or contract relationship, to provide the products and services you have requested. For example, when you register for a test, we will provide certain registration information to entities that administer the tests in your area. If you ask us to, we will disclose your test scores to schools and others.

When you request other services, we will provide your personal data to third parties with whom we arrange for those services to be provided. We may also disclose information to third parties that provide administrative or processing services for us — for example, printing, mailing and/or payment processing.

ETS's use of third parties to provide services to you (e.g., payment services) is subject to the terms of use and privacy policies of those third-party websites and such third parties are responsible or liable for their use of your personal data.   

We may also disclose Personal Information collected on the Website, in accordance with applicable law, to assert or defend our rights and property, to prevent harm to others, to collect a debt, or in response to legal processes such as subpoenas. We may also provide (or reserve the right to provide) Personal Information to credit reporting agencies and to cooperate with law enforcement authorities or other governmental authorities consistent with applicable laws. 

If you have consented to our doing so, we may also share your personal data with third parties in order that they may offer you information about their goods and services.

Because nonpersonal information does not personally identify you, we may use or disclose such information for any purpose. In some instances, we may combine nonpersonal information with Personal Information (such as embedding email addresses in cookies). If we do combine any nonpersonal information with Personal Information, the combined information will be treated by us as Personal Information in accordance with this Policy.

Based upon your specific relationship(s) with ETS, we may disclose your Personal Information in ways described in more detail in one or more Other Agreements. 

Back to Top

## Choice to Opt Out and Access to Your Information

When you register for a test online or create an account, you will have the ability to opt out of receiving certain communications from ETS, including voicemail or email. If you do not opt out at registration, but later decide that you would prefer not to receive email communications from ETS, please contact that particular testing program through www.ets.org. Remember, however, that ETS may still send email or call you in order to provide a product or service that you request.

Except as otherwise specified in an Other Agreement, you can also access your Personal Information to update or correct factual errors in your Personal Information by sending us an email at [etsinfo@ets.org](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org). To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

Back to Top

## Links to Third-party Sites

This Website may contain links to other third-party websites. ETS does not control the privacy policies or practices of these third-party sites. You should review those policies before providing any information. ETS is not responsible for the content or practices of any linked third-party sites, and we provide these links solely for the convenience and information of our visitors. Specifically, if you use a credit card to pay for any products or services, ETS is not responsible for any information you provide regarding the credit card on this Website or by linking through to a credit card processor's website.

Back to Top

## Security

ETS has established safeguards to help prevent unauthorized access to or misuse of your Personal Information, but cannot guarantee that your Personal Information will never be disclosed in a manner inconsistent with this Policy (for example, as a result of unauthorized acts by third parties that violate applicable law or relevant Web policies).

If you register for a Web account, you will be asked to select a password to help protect your information. These passwords help us verify your identity before granting access or making corrections to any of your Personal Information. You should never disclose your password to anyone. ETS will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or email. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and any account information.

When you provide credit card information, it is transmitted using SSL technology to help prevent unauthorized access to or misuse of that information. You will know that SSL is being used when you see a full yellow key in a blue box in the lower left-hand corner of your browser or a full "lock" in the status bar of your Internet Explorer browser.

ETS has contracted with a company to host our [online store](http://store.ets.org/store/ets/DisplayHomePage). This company uses its own Secure Sales Server technology (S3) along with SSL encryption technology on every order transaction. 

Back to Top

## Changes

ETS reserves the right to change this Policy to respond to new laws, regulations or technology, or for other business reasons. Please check this Website from time to time to review any such changes.

Back to Top

## Governing Law and Jurisdiction

You agree that any claim, action or proceeding arising out of this Policy, or your use of the Website, shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the United States and the State of New Jersey, without regard to principles of conflict of laws. Any claim, action or proceeding related to this Policy will be resolved exclusively in the state or federal courts located in the State of New Jersey and you consent to the jurisdiction of those courts.

Back to Top

If you have any questions or concerns about the Website or security policies, you may contact us by:

Email:
Mail:
    ETS  
Rosedale Road  
P.O. Box 6666  
Princeton, NJ 08541-6666  
USA

Back to Top

## Protect Yourself: Watch Out for Online Fraud

### Don't get reeled in.

In a technique called "phishing," thieves set up fraudulent websites that look official. They may send emails to draw you to the site. Often, people visit the site and give Personal Information in an unsecured environment, making Social Security numbers and credit card information available to thieves.

### Note the secure pages.

When you submit Personal Information, there are two (2) things you should look for when you come to secure or safe pages:

  1. A lock symbol or icon will appear on the right side of the bottom bar on the page.
  2. The letters "https" will appear first in your address bar at the very top of the page.

### Don't respond to phony emails.

ETS will **never** send you an email asking for credit card or bank account numbers or any other financial information. If you receive a suspicious message that looks like it came from ETS, do not respond.

ETS frequently sends email promotions and invitations to students and educators. If you follow a link in an email and are directed to a website that is not ETS's official site, do not provide your Personal Information.

### Report fraud immediately.

Send a copy of the suspicious message and any related details to [etsinfo@ets.org](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org).

### What to do if you're a victim:

If you suspect that you may be a victim of phishing:

  * Check with your credit card company and bank to see if anyone else has illegally used your account(s).
  * Change your passwords on all online accounts.
  * Contact the appropriate credit bureaus or agencies to report the incident.
  * Write a letter to the credit card companies, banks and any other institutions or agencies documenting what happened. Keep a copy for yourself.
  * Keep records of everything.

Back to Top

## Special Notice to California Residents

Under California Law SB 27, California residents have the right to receive, once a year, information about third parties with whom we have shared Personal Information about you or your family for their marketing purposes during the previous calendar year, and a description of the categories of Personal Information shared. If you are a California resident and wish to make such a request, please send an email to [etsinfo@ets.org](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org) and include the phrase "California Privacy Request" in the subject line, and provide us with your name, address and email address. We will respond to you within thirty (30) days of receiving such a request. 

Effective Date: July 21, 2011

## See also:

  * Site Terms of Use
  * Privacy and Information Security Policy for Test Takers
